Now, why don't you come with me, tiger boy?
さぁ　一緒に来てもらおうか
虎の少年
It's happening again.
これじゃ前と同じだ
Yet again, I'm...
僕は　また…
Wait.
待って
君は確かポートマフィアの…
Weren't you with the Port Mafia?
違う　私の名は鏡花
I'm not.
My name is Kyouka.
I'm with the Agency.
探偵社員
What a barbaric nation.
なんという野蛮な国だ
こんな少女がこれほどの…
For such a young girl to be so...
You, wait!
おい　待って
Oh, dear.
おやおや
I've been looking for you.
随分捜したんだよ
Where were you all this time?
今までどこに？
In alleyways and slums.
裏路地や貧民街　嘗て私がいた場所
Where I used to be.
But I didn't belong there anymore.
でも　そこはもう私の居場所じゃなかった
I called the city police
from the shop phone.
偽の通報で市警を呼んでおいた
It won't be so easy for the
Guild with the police around.
警察と一緒なら　ギルドも気軽に手は出せない
Kyouka-chan...
鏡花ちゃん
You could have stayed out of the war
if you just stayed missing.
行方不明のままでいれば　戦争に巻き込まれずに済んだのに
私の居場所は探偵社だけだから
The Agency is my only home.
鏡花はじき大勢を殺す
Kyouka will soon kill many people.
So long as her abilities are
darkly entangled within her soul,
才能が鏡花の魂に黒く絡みついている以上
あの子は闇から抜け出せぬ
she will never escape the darkness.
For the first time in my life,
I aspire to be something.
生まれて初めてなりたいものができた
だから戦う
So I will fight.
Even if that means I have to use
everything that lurks within me.
仮令自分の中に潜む何を使っても
They're here.
来た
すいません
Excuse me.
What happened?
何があったんだい
We were attacked with weapons.
武器を持った人達に襲われて
What?
何だって
Captain!
警部
Unit 07 here, calling headquarters.
こちらゼロナナ　本部どうぞ
Headquarters.
こちら本部
Your location?
そちらの現在位置は
第三埠頭です
Dock Three.
We have information that a serial
murderer is on the loose in that area.
手配中の連続殺人犯がその近辺を逃亡中との情報あり
十四歳の少女で和装
A girl of fourteen, dressed in Japanese clothes.
I repeat.
繰り返す
We have information that a serial
murderer is on the loose in that area.
手配中の連続殺人犯がその近辺を逃亡中
十四歳の少女で和装
A girl of fourteen, dressed in Japanese clothes.
How old are you, miss?
お嬢ちゃん
齢は？
Headquarters, we—
本部　こちら…
Captain!
警部
How could you do that?
なんてことするんだ
Captain!
警部　しっかりしてください　警部
Hang in there, Captain!
Requesting backup!
直ぐに応援を
Flawless.
完璧だ
Even the target's escape
measures are accounted for.
標的の逃走対策も万全
Miss Louisa's strategy proposals
are perfect, as always.
相変わらずルイーザ君の作戦書は完璧だな
Guild Operative
Mark T.
Ability: Huck Finn
& Tom Sawyer
大命中
Bullseye.
ゴム製の弾だから死にはしないけど　死ぬほど痛いんだよねぇ
It won't kill you, since it's a rubber
bullet, but it's painful as hell.
ご苦労様　マーク君
Good work, Mark.
では　小公女
Well then, my little princess,
I'm taking your boyfriend.
ボーイフレンドはいただいていくぞ
No!
駄目　それだけは…
Anything but that!
ハーマン君
Mr. Herman.
Understood.
承知した
Guild Operative
Herman M.
Ability:
Moby Dick
久しいなぁ　相棒
It's been a long time, my friend.
君とは会ったばかりだが
We've only just met,
人生経験から忠告しよう　小公女
but allow me to give you some
life advice, my little princess.
You aren't cut out for helping people.
君に人助けは向いていない
向いているのは…
I assume you understand
what you are cut out for.
わかるな
Why?
ならどうして…
どうして光を見せたの？
Why did you show me the light?
どうして望みを抱かせたの？
Why did you give me hope?
Hands up!
手をあげろ
連続殺人の容疑で逮捕する
You're under arrest on
suspicion of serial murder.
さようなら
Goodbye.
Episode 20
Though the Head May Err
もう私を…光で照らさないで
Please don't give me any more light.
And a week has passed...
Let's play.
あっそぼう　なーにしてあっそぼう
What should we do?
矢っ張り外っていいなあ
It's so fun being outside.
There's one!
みーつけた
ねえ　おじさん
Hey, Mister, let's have fun.
僕を楽しませてよ
You're from the Guild, aren't you?
おじさん　ギルドの人でしょ
楽しませる？
Have fun?
子どもを？
With a child?
Here you are, a dachshund.
ダックスフンド　やろう
要らない
No thanks.
Okay, now it's my turn.
じゃあ　次は僕の番ね
えいえいえーい
Boop, boop, boop!
ジャーン
Ta-da.
Look, you get that handprint
when you hurt me.
僕を傷つけた人には　その手形が現れるんだよ
Now, show me, Mister...
さぁ　見せてよ　おじさん
Show me complete madness.
とびっきりの狂気を
私にはよくわからない
I don't get it.
狂気とは　これのことか
Is this what you mean by madness?
You've been sleeping well, pastor.
よく寝たな　牧師殿
Lord Francis.
フランシス様
気分はどうかな
How do you feel?
マーガレットは
Where's Margaret?
In critical condition.
重傷だ
She may never wake up.
二度と目覚めんかもしれん
愚かな女性だ
What a foolish woman.
She protected me in the end.
彼女は最後に私を庇った
That's how I survived.
だから私は助かったのです
Margaret said she would take
back her family's honor.
マーガレットは一族の名誉を取り戻すと云っていた
それなのに何故…
So why...
彼女は一族の莫大な負債を返済し　家名を立て直す為に作戦に参加した
She joined the operation in
order to repay her family's
massive debt and re-establish
their reputation.
Alas, that's nothing more
than a fleeting dream.
まぁ　その夢も今や消えゆく澪泡だが
消えたのではない
It was never fleeting.
貴方が消したのですよ　フランシス様
Not until you made it so, Lord Francis.
何だと
What?
もはや貴方には頼らない
I will depend on you no longer.
I will take back her honor myself.
彼女の名誉は　必ず私が取り戻す
ルイーザ君
Ms. Louisa.
緊急プランを見せろ
Show me the emergency plan.
But that plan will cause a
lot of collateral damage.
でもあれは他のプランに較べ　現地民被害が最悪値です
It'll turn Yokohama into a sea of flames.
横浜が焼け野原になります
ここにある物は凡て俺の所有物だ
Everything here belongs to me.
The ship, the desk, the pens,
the window dressing...
船　机　ペン　窓の日除けに至るまで
And you and my other people, too, of course.
無論　君や他の部下もだ
Thus, I won't allow my people
to be hurt any more.
故にこれ以上　部下が傷つくことは許さん
As you are my property,
I have the right to protect you.
俺には俺の所有物である君達を守る権利がある
Notify everyone that the
emergency plan is in effect.
緊急プラン発動を全員に通達しろ
は…はい
Y-Yes, sir.
I'll end this in the blink of an eye.
一瞬で終わらせてやる
Dachshund.
ダックスフンド
Hey, how's it coming?
やぁ　調子はどう？
痛い　僕の体が
My body...
It hurts.
まぁ　恨むならこの緊急プランを考えた作戦参謀か
Well, if you're looking for someone to blame,
try the officers who made this emergency plan,
あのラヴクラフトの精神を破壊するなんて莫迦を仕掛けた君自身を恨みなよ
or yourself for coming up with the foolish
idea of trying to destroy Lovecraft's mind.
I'll kill you.
殺す
I'll kill you!
殺してやる
いってー
Ow!
Are you enjoying your
cruise on the Moby Dick?
「白鯨」の船旅は気に入ったか
Excuse me.
失礼します
Why is she here?
彼女は…
Oh, Ms. Lucy?
あぁ　ルーシー君か
手の内を知られた異能力者に戦術価値はないのだが
She has no strategic value, given that her
trick's known now, but she insisted on staying.
本人がどうしても残りたいと云うのでな
Now, where were we?
却説　本題に戻ろう
我々はある「本」を捜している
We're looking for a book.
A book?
本？
There's only a single copy in the world.
世界にただ一冊のみ存在する本だ
It's said to be impervious to any degree
of firepower or special abilities.
どんな炎や異能力でも傷つかないとされている
Someone with a gift foresaw that it would
be found sealed away here in Yokohama.
その本がこの横浜の地に封印されているとある異能力者が予知した
What does that book have to do with me?
その本と僕に何の関係が…
You're literally the tiger
beetle... The guide post.
君が文字通り「タイガービートル」
つまり　道標だからだよ
君をここに招いたのも　眼下の街と一緒に灰になられては困るからだ
In fact, I brought you here because
I couldn't have you turning to ashes
along with the rest of the city.
なに
What?
The Gifted Special Operations
Division is neutralized.
異能特務課は無力化した
All that's left is the Armed Detective
Agency and the Port Mafia.
残るは武装探偵社とポートマフィアだが
この二組織は非常に厄介でな
These two organizations
happen to be quite a pain.
街ごと焼くことにした
We've decided to burn down the entire city.
そのほうが後々の捜し物も楽だ
It'll make our search easier as well.
そんな強力な異能力あるわけが…
No one has such a powerful gift!
これに見覚えがあるだろう
Does this not look familiar?
Said emergency plan is, basically,
a combo of our two abilities.
緊急プランっていうのはね
要するに　君と僕との異能力連携さ
僕の「葡萄」は宿主と他の樹木とを中継し　感覚を共有する能力だ
My gift gives me the ability to share
senses between a host and other trees,
across my vines.
今回は横浜凡ての樹木を君に接合した
I've connected every tree
in Yokohama to you.
そうとも知らない人々はいつも通り
The unwitting go on as usual,
walking on the roots,
木の根を踏み　幹を叩き　枝を切り落としている
hitting the trunks,
and cutting down branches.
That pain is being sent
into you as we speak.
その痛覚信号が今も君に流れ込んでいるわけだ
Now, it's time for a quiz.
却説　ここで問題
What do you think will happen to the city
if you engage your curse right now?
君が今詛いの力を発動したら　街はどうなると思う
この人形の頭を破くと　街の約２０％の人間に詛いが発動する
The moment I rip this doll's head off,
roughly 20 percent of the town will be cursed.
これが緊急プラン
This is the emergency plan.
Also known as the Yokohama
Incineration Operation.
別名　「横浜焼却作戦」だ
君の街は滅びる　君の所為でね
Your town will be destroyed,
all because of you.
Why?
どうして…
I never asked for this ability.
こんな力　欲しいと思ったことなんて一度もない
なのに　どうしていつも僕ばかりこんな非道いことが起こるの
So why do all these terrible
things happen because of me?
神様は誰にでも平等じゃないの
Isn't everyone equal in
the eyes of the Lord?
You're right.
そうだね
けど　それがこの世界なんだ
But this is the world we live in.
So let me tell you the truth:
だから本当のことを教えよう
神様はいるよ
God exists.
But He doesn't love you.
でも　君を愛してはいない
嫌だ
No!
No! No!
嫌だ　嫌だ　そんな世界焼き尽くしてやる
I'll burn this world down!
呪われてあれ　呪われてあれ
I'll curse it!
呪われてあれ
Say, dear.
ねぇ　あなた
Yes?
Did you always have that scar?
そんな痣あった
Looks like it's begun.
始まったか
All I need to do now is to destroy
this doll and trigger the ability.
後はこの人形を破壊し　異能力発動のトリガーとするだけ
わかった
Okay!
おい
I surrender!
降参する
The Agency and I will help
you unconditionally.
あなた達の捜し物に僕も探偵社も全面協力する
So please don't destroy the doll!
だから　その人形を破壊するのだけは
I see.
なるほど　興味深い提案だ
That is an interesting proposal.
よし　協力体制を築こう
Very well. Let's form a
cooperative framework.
But only with the survivors.
ただし　生き残った奴とな
Damn, traffic jam.
渋滞か
平和ですね
It's so peaceful.
どこがだ
How is it peaceful?
What the hell?!
何だこいつ
殺す　殺す
Minoura-san!
箕浦さん
出せ
Let me out!
Damn it.
クソ
The city... I need to do something.
このままじゃ街が…
あら　ゴミ捨てのついでに見に来てみれば
Oh my, I came to check on you
on my way to the garbage.
いい気味だわ
This is a pleasant sight.
君は…
You're...
Please.
頼む　ここを開けてくれ
Let me out of here.
い・や・よ
No way.
I hate privileged people like you.
あなたみたいな恵まれた人は大嫌い
このまま街が灰になって
Maybe you'll know how I feel
when the city burns down and you're
discarded like this useless doll.
あなたがこのボロ人形みたいに用なしになって捨てられたら
あたしの気持ちがわかるでしょうね
I know your pain well.
君の辛さはよくわかるよ
僕だって…
知った風な口利かないで
Don't talk like you know!
Have you washed dishes all
day with bloody fingers?
血の滲む指で一日皿洗いしたことはある
Have you ever been tortured
with a hot iron poker?
熱した火掻き棒で折檻されたことは
Do you have any idea how much pain
and agony these scars give me?
この傷の痛みと苦しみがどんなものか　あなたに想像できて
On the first day, it's the bone that hurts.
一日目に痛むのは骨
But it's the third day
that it hurts the most.
でも一番きついのは三日目だ
The burn chafes every time you move.
動くたびに火傷が擦れて死ぬほど痛む
It hurts like hell.
I was there, too.
僕も同じ場所にいた
I know your fear and loneliness well.
だから君の怯えも孤独もよくわかるよ
But loneliness wasn't a king
lording over us forever.
でも孤独は　僕達を永遠に支配する王様ではなかった
Loneliness is just a soft, puffy cloud
forming and vanishing on a whim.
孤独は時に消え　時に現れるただの朧雲だ
地上にも僕達と同じ傷を抱えた人が沢山いる
Many people on the ground
carry wounds the way we do.
Abandon them, and you're
abandoning your past self.
その人達を見捨てれば　君は
君は過去の自分も見捨てることになる
Is that what you want?
それでもいいのかい
ここは…
Where am I?
It's too late.
手遅れよ　もう横浜は終わり
Yokohama's done.
No, there's still a way.
いいや　まだ手はある
Dazai-san only needs to touch
the doll to end the curse.
太宰さんの異能力でその人形に触れれば　詛いは消滅する
あんた　莫迦なの
Are you stupid?
We're in the sky.
ここは空の上なのよ
どうやって人形を渡すつもりよ
How do you think you're
going to give him the doll?
I see.
そう…
You're doing it.
やるのね
You'll get shot and killed by anti-air guns.
対空砲に撃たれて死ぬか　地面に叩きつけられて死ぬか
Or you'll hit the ground and die.
地上の狂った人達に引き裂かれて死ぬか
Or you'll get shredded up by
the madmen on the ground.
You know those are your only options,
and you're still going to do it.
どれかしかないとわかっていても　やるのね
There was an old book at the orphanage.
孤児院で読んだ古い本にあったよ
It said, "I've never regretted
anything I've done."
「昔　私は自分のした事に就いて後悔したことはなかった」
「しなかった事に就いてのみ　何時も後悔を感じていた」
"I've only ever regretted the
things that I didn't do."
あの本　書いた人の名は何と云っただろうか
What was the name of the author?
It's a parachute.
落下傘よ
I kept one hidden in case
I needed to escape.
万一逃げる時の為に一つ隠しておいたの
I connected the white door
to Moby Dick's plating.
白いドアを「白鯨」の外壁に繋げたわ
Really?
いいの　僕を逃がしたら　君はギルドから…
The Guild won't let you
off for letting me go.
独りぼっちは最初からですもの
I've always been lonely.
Besides, as long as I'm
in this room, I'm safe.
それにこの部屋にいる限り　あたしは安全よ
ねぇ　君は本当に大丈夫なの
Hey, are you really going to be safe?
I know you're invulnerable in this room.
確かにこの部屋の中なら君は無敵だ
But doesn't that mean you
can never leave this room?
でもそれって　この部屋から永遠に出られないってことじゃ
察しの悪い人ね　ちょっとした口実よ
You're so dense.
It's just an excuse.
生きて
Live.
And save me from this place someday.
そして　いつかあたしをここから救い出して
I'll be waiting.
待ってるから
All right.
わかった
The tiger has escaped.
虎が逃げた
To your stations!
至急持ち場につけ
繰り返す
I repeat.
虎が逃げた
The tiger has escaped.
Prepare anti-air cannons.
空対空カノン用意
It's...
あれは
交通網を死守しろ
Control the traffic!
このままだとうちが商売する場所まで灰になっちまう
We won't have anywhere left to do business.
死ぬ気で守れ
Protect it with your life!
I see.
そうか　そういうことか
So that's what's happening.
Now, then.
却説
Mark here can hit a falling
target, no problem.
このマーク様にかかれば　落下中の標的を捉えるなんて楽勝さ
見つけたぜ
Peek-a-boo.
なんだ
What the...
Tom has captured the target.
トムが標的を捉えました
グーッボーイ　トム
Good boy, Tom!
All right, Huck, load the second shell.
それじゃ　ハック　クールに次弾装填
Yes, sir.
了解
砲口　初速よし
Trajectory and firing velocity, check.
母艦との相対速度　修正よし
Compensating for relative velocity
with target body, check.
ハックの砲弾が落下傘をぶち抜いたぜ
Huck's shot ripped through the parachute.
イエーイ
Yeah!
So, how's the tiger boy?
で　タイガーボーイは
Passed out from the blast.
衝撃波で気絶　こりゃ地面衝突で粉々コースだな
It looks like he's going to hit the
ground and be smashed to bits.
殺さないって指示はどうしたよ
What happened to your order not to kill him?
死体さえ残ってれば　本国の異能力者が何とかするでしょ
I'm sure his own country's gifteds will
figure it out, as long as his body's still there.
矢っ張り無理なのか
So I really am no use.
There's nothing I can do.
結局　僕には何も…
お前か
It's you.
そうだよな
Of course.
You despise me, don't you?
お前は僕が嫌いだよな
I hate me, too.
僕も僕が嫌いだ
Thanks for everything.
今まで　ありがとな
I'm alive.
生きてる
I have to deliver it!
早く届けなくちゃ
I need to stop it immediately.
一刻も早くこれを止めないと
凄いな
Amazing.
He survived a huge fall, and my rain of
bullets won't so much as scratch him.
超高度からの落下に耐えて　弾丸の雨に掠りもしない
I guess he's that desperate
to deliver that gross doll.
そんだけあのキモ人形を届けたいってことじゃねぇの
ならこれは狩りじゃあない
This isn't a hunt, then.
This is a duel between two men.
男と男の決闘だ
What?
なんだ
あんなもの前からあったっけ
Has that thing always been here?
I don't recommend losing
your focus, tiger boy.
余所見はオススメしないね　タイガーボーイ
There's no telling from which
way trouble will come.
ピンチはどこから来るかわからないよ
燃料輸送車
An oil truck!
終わりだね
It's over.
Stop resisting.
無駄な足掻きはやめろ
それが貴様の限界だ
You've reached your limit.
Shut up.
五月蝿い
You win, Atsushi-kun.
君の勝ちだよ　敦君
太宰さん
Dazai-san...
ここは危険です　空からの銃撃が
It's dangerous here.
They'll shoot you from above.
I wonder about that.
それはどうかな
煙幕
Smoke?
That's not all.
それだけじゃねぇぞ
熱センサー　探査レーダー無効
Heat sensors and radars disabled.
It's a sensor jammer.
これは飽和チャフです
人形を届ける為に彼が落ちてくると信じて街中に仕込んでいたのか
He's been setting them up all over town
believing he'd be coming with the doll?
You got me.
完敗だね
Good job, Atsushi-kun.
よくやったよ　敦君
Yokohama is saved.
これで　横浜は安全だ
Or so I wish.
…と云いたいところだが
But as long as the enemy have Q,
Ｑが敵の手にある限り　連中は何度でもこの大破壊を繰り返せる
they'll repeat this carnage
as many times as they need.
Now, what do we do?
却説　どうしたものか
Dazai-san, I'm reminded of a line
from a book I read a long time ago.
太宰さん
昔読んだ本に　こんな一節があったことを思い出しました
"The head may err, but never the blood."
「頭は間違うことがあっても血は間違わない」
I have an idea.
ある発想を思いついたんです
It may seem out of the
question to everyone else.
みんなからすれば論外な発想かもしれない
Yet to me, to my blood and soul,
it seems like the only correct answer.
でも僕にはそれが　僕の血と魂が示す唯一の正解に思えてならないんです
どんな発想だい
What's the idea?
An alliance.
協力者です
They're the most powerful in Yokohama,
and they're trying to defend this city.
彼らはこの横浜で尤も強く　そしてこの街を守りたがっています
There's no better organization to
help us in our fight against the Guild.
ギルドと戦っていくうえで　協力者としてこれ以上の組織はありません
And which organization is that?
その組織の名は？
ポートマフィアです
ポートマフィアが武装探偵社と手を組む？
Episode Twenty-One
Double Black
The Port Mafia.
この街に生き　この街を守る組織として
"The head may err, but never the blood." -
Nakajima Atsushi, in Light, Wind and Dreams
異国の異能力者に街を焼かせるわけにはゆかぬ
果たして過去の遺恨を超えた同盟が可能となるかな
万一そうなれば　黒社会最強のあのコンビが復活ということになるね
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第二十一話
双つの黒
相変わらずの幼女趣味か